Benjamin Stratton

Software Engineer

Benstratton100@gmail.com | +1(808)646-1106 | www.benjamin-stratton.com | www.linkedin.com/in/benjaminbstratton

Summary

A data-driven Software Engineer combining bootcamp experience and a sales/marketing background to develop high-performing, top-quality full-stack applications.

Skills & Tools

Javascript, Python, HTML/CSS, NoSQL, SQL, React, Node.js, Django, Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind, JSON, MongoDB, Postgresql, Agile Methodologies, Wireframing, Testing, Github, VScode, Slack, Figma, Postman, Trello.

Experience

Build Your Practice | Business Consultant April 2022 - December 2022

Build Your Practice is a consulting firm that offers assistance to mental health clinicians seeking to establish and sustain successful private practices. As the leading business consultant, I assumed the responsibility of devising and directing lead generation strategies, as well as providing expert guidance throughout the entire sales cycle.

- → Revamped the sales cycle and executed novel systems resulting in a 500% surge in sales.
- → Impacted the lives of more than 100 clinicians by providing tailored services that facilitated a twofold increase in monthly earnings within a span of three months.

Freelance | High Ticket Sales Closer August 2021 - April 2022

In my capacity as a freelance high ticket closer, I assumed the onus of proactively identifying and nurturing qualified leads through the intricacies of the sales funnel, with the overarching goal of meeting and exceeding weekly and monthly key performance indicators (KPIs).

→ Demonstrated an exceptional aptitude for high-value sales by surpassing the milestone of \$500k in cash collected within the initial eight months of my tenure.

Projects

Push-It - Workout App

With over 3+ years of personal training experience and several more in my own personal training regimen, I have consistently been asked to share routines and tips for getting started! Therefore, Push-it was born to do two fundamental things: provide sample workout routines and a space to track workouts!

- → Created with a Postgres database, Node.js, Express.js, React, Material UI, JWT, bcrypt, and much more!
- → Includes user authentication, email and password verification, private routes, user quiz that generates custom feedback, and full CRUD for storing information.

https://github.com/benjaminstratton/pushIt workoutApp

Restaurant Finder

How many times have you gone down a rabbit hole trying to figure out where to eat? Restaurant Finder solves that problem by providing you a platform to view highly rated restaurants and add your own picks as well!

- → Created with Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose, EJS, and Bootstrap!
- → Full CRUD application with curated data and a focus on design.

https://github.com/benjaminstratton/restaurantFinder

Education

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive 2023-2023

Successfully completed an intensive 500+ hour Software Engineering Immersive course, acquiring expertise in technical skills, research and analysis, project management, and collaborative teamwork.

Western Carolina University Integrated Health Sciences 2018 - 2021